{
    "id": "810c89406a804f8581fee2530e30086c",
    "title": "Conditionals Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "If I were you I ............................................ pay 200 dollars for that coat.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "won't",
                "wouldn't"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ............................................ red and green, you get yellow.",
            "description": "In a zero conditional sentence, we use a simple present tense in both clauses. The zero conditional is used to talk about real situations.",
            "answers": [
                "mix",
                "will mix",
                "would mix"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If I had known about the consequences, I .............................................. it.",
            "description": "In the third conditional we use a past perfect in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will never do",
                "would never do",
                "would never have done"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Unless you get enough rest, you .............................................. ill.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will fall",
                "would fall",
                "would have fallen"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "............................................ I known, I would have helped.",
            "description": "This is similar to 'If I had known, I would have helped'. In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if clause and would have  + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "Had",
                "Were",
                "Should"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Unless you .............................................. gambling, you will face many problems.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "quit",
                "will quit",
                "would quit"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If I knew her name, I .............................................. you.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will tell",
                "would tell",
                "would have told"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If she knew you, why .............................................. she say Hi?",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "don't",
                "didn't",
                "hadn't"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "................................................. your help, I would have been in real trouble.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "But for",
                "If only"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I ............................................. retire if I won the lottery.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "would",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "How .............................................. you react if you were in my position?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "would",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You will catch cold if you .......................................... out without a coat.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "go",
                "will go",
                "went"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}